oh I cut that off real quick welcome to
the hustle zone so um hi folks how are
you doing my name is Ryan Perez owner
and founder of bowai creative where we
donate free websites to entrepreneurs
with disabilities so every website that
we sell we donate uh we donate uh uh
websites to entrepreneurs with
disabilities um it started off with uh
uh my you know now he's a client of mine
Michael uh D Haynes and uh you know he
at the time was making $900 a month and
couldn't afford to do the marketing and
I said you know what I'm tired of people
not being able to have the option of
making money I mean I I like government
you know I like that there are some
government assistant programs but I also
feel that we also have the opportunity
to make like we all have the opportunity
to make it but some people don't have
that opportunity so I really want to
encourage you I don't just do the hustle
Zone just because I I you know you know
I you know not not just because I like
it but I also want to send the word out
that we need to help people within our
communities so please DM me if you know
someone that needs a website um that
could qualify and I'm not looking for
someone that has a disability but
they're like super rich I mean and let's
just like I'm looking for for people
that don't really have the opportunity
you know um that they're stuck in the
system those are the people that I want
to help uh so okay um I've been working
out i' I'm getting rid of those movs I
think that uh you know like I'm starting
to see more definition in the ABS just
by just clean eating I just went cold
turkey just went right in 17 days in and
I'm starting to see results so you guys
can see the results on my page I know
it's embarrassing man I saw myself
kicking the kicking bag and it was
embarrassing cuz I'm like you know you
know men women look at the like they
look at the uh the the mirror and
they're like am I fat men are like man I
look great but then when you see
yourself kicking a bag and you see like
you're like super fat you're like oh man
so like you know like I have this
complex but you know it's always great
when you're looking at yourself in 2D
right but as soon as you put that third
dimension in there it paints a whole
different picture so I am loving the the
honesty that I'm giving you all um but
it's it's encouraging because a lot of
you guys have been encouraging giving me
really good food tips and I feel great
like even my delivery just the way I
look I look at myself and I just feel
more vibrant so thank you guys if you
guys want to participate in the
challenge Susan day has been doing it
okay she's been posting herself doing
squats and stuff I mean if if Susan can
do it if I can do it you can do it so if
you want if you're worried about health
and you want remember I remember all you
guys in 2017 before it hit you're like
mhm the new the new me this is the new
Me Oh Our Guest our our guest left but
we're going to get her back but this is
the new
me um but then I don't see nothing I
don't see any I don't see any of you
guys talking about anything you know
what I mean I don't see you really doing
much at all so try your best try your
best to you know put your challenge out
there for everybody to see because
that's the only way in this world where
like putting it on social media is
definitely going to hold you accountable
because if you came in looking like um
uh Kool-Aid
man you know best believe that you have
to you have to look different by 2018 if
you're putting it on social media
because people won't let you forget and
I know that you guys are not going to
let me forget so that's what's holding
me to the
fire so today today's show is amazing
because this is a woman that has gone
through a lot in her
life however it doesn't appear so she's
like you know I know it doesn't appear
that I've gone through a lot but you
know I you know my response to that is
that sometimes sometimes some people are
just chosen to be the light of the world
and when you see them they just light
you up because that's part of their gift
so when every time time I see Jamie she
lights me up she makes me feel great you
know what I mean and she always reminds
you to keep on the positive because
sometimes I get vexed at certain things
and she comes in and she just like
mhm you're the hustle Zone baby look at
what you've accomplished you need to
stay on the right path okay so the first
obvious thing and that you're going to
notice is that she's beautiful right she
has great looks um but but what she will
tell you is that God gave me
those right
and it's not the thing is is that some
people could be like thank you I know I
look so beautiful but she says that God
gave me those right she is acknowledging
I mean I'm not personally religious but
I I am an agnostic theist I do believe
and but I believe when people say
certain things and when you say that
gave me that gift then she realizes that
that gift can be used either for
negative or it could be used for a
positive and that and like I said when
you see her she just lights you up she
has a great personality but she has a
lot of wisdom packed behind that and she
has a really raw story you know you know
and her being a mother and putting all
of her passion in what she's doing she's
written two books and put in she put she
dedicated those books to her
daughters you know because she wanted
them to be a a great example and she
wanted her daughters to follow the path
to God to Christ that's what she says
okay so this is very interesting hustle
Zone because this is a
entrepreneur that is an advocate for you
know for
spirituality and so this is going to be
hustle every hustle zone is a Twist cuz
yesterday was a Twist the day before was
a Twist you know every hustle zone is a
Twist I I want to welcome you to the
hustle Zone Jamie
Lynn oh and she is not CED up oh there
she is hey how are you doing okay so can
you
unmute okay all right so are you there
oh try it again
there we go we good yeah we're good so
how are you doing I'm wonderful what an
introduction that was thank you so much
yeah you know I every introduction I try
to I try to capture the essence of the
person as much as I possibly can because
that's the only way I'm going to
resonate you know with the interview
because the the like the hustle zone is
really raw it's about chemistry right
because yeah right it's just about
getting to the the core of the
entrepreneur and so I have to tell this
every time it's we humanize the
entrepreneur rurs to show that we're all
human beings however we have different
habits the habits make us who we are and
so Jamie we're just going to cut to the
chase because I know you have a hell of
a story and we don't have much time so
I'm one I'm I'm this is all you so the
first question I'm going to ask you and
everyone's going to get mad if I don't
ask this question but what is your story
what is my story well first of all I I
want to let you know I have a five-page
spread in a book called leading ladies
that is basically my childhood testimony
and in that book um I talk about how I
was physically and sexually abused as a
child I was raped when I was five and um
we got taken away from my mom when I was
uh 10 years old and put in foster care
got to go back home and then my mom
became very abusive like she was very
physically abusive and they took us away
again and I ended up being put in a
group home and then after I got out of
the group home I bounced around from
foster home to foster
home um at the age of 18 I got pregnant
had an abortion got pregnant at 19 put
her up for adoption and then at 20 um I
have my 20 year old and um when I was
she was nine months old and then I got
into stripping and did that for four
years and the last year of that I got
into drugs and alcohol um I tried to
commit suicide twice uh it it's just
it's such a scroll of things and then um
at 25 because I was so heavy into drugs
I got pregnant again so I ultimately had
an abortion at 25 So when you say I
don't look like what I've been through I
don't you know and it was a three-week
Bene I was on up in Omaha Nebraska and I
write about it in my book matter of fact
the story is in both of my books
um that I watched my cousin Brandy get
beat up by four girls and two guys and
it was probably one of the most horrific
things I've ever seen in my life and I
said I need to change my life and I went
home um I looked up pain in the back of
the Bible and there was Jeremiah 15:15
through 21 telling me if I Repent I'll
be a spokesperson for God and I gave my
life to the Lord not knowing what I was
getting into at that time um I gave my
life to the Lord and and just you know
walked out the process and that's how I
got saved um I went home and just
completely changed my life and and
that's where diamond and the rough comes
in you know because people think when
you get saved that you're just you know
why are you still drinking why are you
still doing drugs why are you still
having sex because I think what happens
when you get saved you don't completely
understand what the word surrender
surrender all means right you know and
and and you got to be willing to
surrender some of those things and I
wasn't willing to surrender that I
wasn't you know um and and diamond in
the rough is me talking about my
marriage I I married somebody I
shouldn't have married and and my
drinking issues that I had with that and
the relationship with you know my
daughter my 20-year-old that there was
some things that happened there that I I
still to this day deal with some of the
after the consequences of the choices
that I made during that time but you
know
um I have just learned that you know no
matter what my favorite verse right now
like of all time is all things work
together for our good for those who love
him I absolutely love that verse because
it is so true no matter what adversity
comes your way you know it always turns
out to for your good I would go through
everything that I ever went through in
my life again this the the rape the
sexual abuse the physical abuse if it
meant for one person to get into the
Kingdom of Heaven because that's what
it's about it's not about Jamie I could
be a victim in this all day long but
that's not going to do anything
everything that I went through was
ordained for me to be here today and
talk about it on your show and and share
my story and say you know what if I can
get through it so can
you wow so um you know something
resonated from what you said there uh
with your story
um you you noticed your um your cousin
getting beat up by four girls and two
guys and two guys yes and um I you know
I had a a similar moment where kind of
spooked me because I I saw uh when I was
young we went to beat up some
guy and went outside and I watched my
friends beat this guy up all of them and
like it was it was across the street of
this like um this park where like a like
construction park or whatever and there
was just construction materials and they
were using that and I saw a guy pick up
a stone and throw it right at the guy's
face and yeah I was like spooked and
realized that put me in in in and didn't
realize until now like it put me in
depression it it made me change because
I was like
I don't want that on me yeah I don't
want that on anybody anybody else but
you know and I and you know it's so
funny because I went to I went to God
after I you know I started going to
church after that with my friend's mom
um that didn't last too long but it it
um I still you know I I still felt like
there needed to be a change now I'm
going to this is a raw show so I'm going
to ask some questions that a lot of
people were thinking but they wouldn't
ask
usually when people do drugs they're
prostitutes or they strip or they're
gangsters the first thing that they do
is they go to God and is and and a lot
of people would say well you know
because I I guess there's a conception
that you know God will just save you of
all your sins you know so if I just go
to God and if I pray to God that my Sims
will be wiped away and I'm I'm Scott
clean what's your response to that
because a lot of people would be
thinking that you know that would
be that would be the first thing most
people do when they get into a lot of
trouble um it wasn't that I was in
trouble it was I was at the end of
myself right and I had grown up you know
in just different foster homes where I I
I was introduced to Christ but I wanted
nothing to do with it so you got to
understand that what happened was those
were seeds planted that I was not aware
of at the time and flourished later so
it was it was God saying okay now is the
time you know I was at the end of
myself then I went to God and then the
process began you know it wasn't that I
was doing drugs and and I just came to
God like that no it was like I've got to
change or I'm gonna end up dead I'm
going to end up prostituting and my
child who did not ask to be brought in
into this world is going to be without a
mother that was the reality so it was
either go home and change my life or be
dead or strung out on drugs or the other
alternative and and like I talk about in
my book you know everybody has a journey
you know even when you get saved your
walk with Christ is not a Sprint it's a
marathon you know you're gonna you're
gonna you're going to trip you're gonna
fall you're G to skin your knee get back
up you know and and when people say sin
i i i i they take that in such a broad
spectrum there's so many different
things people sin all the time just like
when people say I don't go to church
because there's a bunch of Hypocrites in
church well what I do when when people
say that to me you know what I say who
hurts you in the church that you feel
like they're Hypocrites because we we
put these people in church and in
leadership on these pedestals that
they're to be perfect when actually it's
quite the opposite it's imperfect people
going to a savior that is perfect to do
the right to do the right things does
that make sense yeah that that makes a
lot of sense and I've never heard that
heard it that way um before because I
mean a lot of us you know I was brought
up in uh I was brought up in the church
um but I was Catholic and want I wanted
to be a priest and everything I I and I
I found my I met my father for the first
time in November 2015 and and to realize
that my grandfathers before me were all
ministers and so you know this Gift of
Gab and being able to motivate and stuff
like that I know where that comes from
but yeah the
um so I've I've seen the hypocrisy you
know with the church and with the people
in it but you know when you realize U my
my mentor he's a man of God uh a
spiritualist and he says that God unites
and the devil divides you know and
when we think about Jesus Jesus wasn't
hanging out with all of the you know the
the purified ones he was hanging out
with those who who no needed purifying
yes you know he he was going to the
[ __ ] and he was going to the
prostitutes and here's the thing you
know and and when you see my videos and
in your introduction you know you're
like I exude you know happiness and Jo
that comes from God I wasn't always like
this I used to be the mean girl and I
would fight you and beat you up and not
think twice about it but because I have
changed and I just my purpose and my
mission in life is to inspire and love
people you know our example in the Bible
is Jesus Jesus loved people and he he
healed them and he met them right where
they were you know what I mean why are
we not meeting people right where they
are you know I'm going to love you I'm
not going to enable to you enable you to
stay where you are but I'm going to tell
you you know what I love you but let's
get you out of this how do how do we get
you out of and and and I think that's my
mission in life is to love people but
not enable them in the sin or whatever
they're in at that time but I'm I'm one
of the people I'll be raw and real with
you I'm not gonna I'm not gonna you know
suar coat and and and do all that
because nobody did that for me you know
I have people in my life that tell me um
Jamie you know no that's not your place
Jamie you know you shouldn't have said
that or you shouldn't do this and and
you know there are things I still you
know I still struggle with you know
there was things that I just laid down
you know and and we just cannot ever
judge a book by its cover because
there's stories in the Bible and and the
stories in the Bible are guidelines for
us to learn from other people's mistakes
not to use it against people for people
to do what you want them to do
manipulate and you know what I mean so
me it's like I I take the word I use it
as my circle and if I step out of that
Circle then then you know there's
consequences for that but I stay in my
circle the realm of boundaries that God
has for me and and Inspire and love
people and try to change people's
lives that's that's that's powerful and
I again you you you perfectly executed
you know your answers there because I
think that you've had a lot of time to
think this through and and you're
minister is is that correct oh I I
haven't got that title got you're a
minister for God or yes I I do I do
speak about God all the time yes
absolutely and so when it came to
um when it came to your relationships
with your daughters now um
because I'm a parent I understand what
it's like to be an entrepreneur and then
to be a father and and then just
consciously being aware that there's
another human being that loves me that
uncon
additionally um you know when you had to
give when you had to give up your
daughter for adoption what was what what
was going on in your mind like how are
you feeling cuz me being a parent you
know that's hard for me to take but if
if I was in that situation I would have
done the same thing you know like how
were you feeling during that
time um
wow in that that time I think there was
a lot of emotions going on because you
got to understand something it wasn't
like I said okay I'm putting her up for
adoption and when I have her I don't
want to see her nothing no I went
through the whole process I cleaned her
I changed her I slept with her I fed her
and when it was time to go um leave the
hospital I placed her in the back of the
that's still emotional for me to this
day you know talking about that because
it's it's it's such a raw emotional
feeling that you put your child to to be
with another family and it that to me
was um unconditional love I wanted her
to have more than I could give her at
that time and um I have a great
relationship with her now she's a
beautiful matter of fact if you put us
side by side we would look like sisters
instead of mother daughters like we look
so identical and she has an amazing
little boy he's just absolutely adorable
and so I mean God has allowed us to
restore our relationship and we do talk
about things and um I'm so grateful for
her adopted parents we had an open
adoption you know and um so it that that
was the key thing for me it was like I
needed to know that she was okay so it
was an open adoption I got to see her um
when she was about two weeks old and
then again when she was about a year old
and then they left from my hometown and
moved away so um it's it's just been one
of those things that you did what I I
did what I had to do at that time you
know and I felt that that was in Riley's
best interest but I'm so beyond grateful
that she allows me to be a part of her
life today because I just absolutely
adore and love her you know and when you
have to depart from someone that you
love you know I think that the power of
spirituality and the Power of Love
allows you to do the things that may not
be in your best
interest but if it's in the best
interest of the of that person that you
love it there's no
regret yeah well and I wasn't saved then
but one of my requirements for her
parents was that they be saved how
ironic is that um and her dad was
actually a minister so you know I knew
that God would be poured into her not
knowing what I was asking for at that
time
but God knew what he was doing so um
it's it it just has all worked out for
all of us um you know my 20-year-old is
living in Washington Briana and um they
talk they they're in communication so
it's just beautiful just just it's and
one day I'll get to sit down with Riley
and we'll get to share our story and
we'll get to go through those raw
emotions that we I think there's some
stuff that we still need to talk out and
and and we have talked a lot of things
out but you know I just truly believe
that our relationship is you know is
amazing and it's going to continue to be
amazing as long as we're both open and
honest with our emotions and feelings
and stuff but I absolutely am crazy
about her all my girls I just I love
being a mom and that was not something I
ever planned on being either I I always
said I don't want to be a mom I didn't I
I didn't want to do that but God knew
what he was doing when he gave gave me
three daughters you know um so I just
you know I'm blessed I'm just I'm just
blessed to have the privilege to be a
mom oh yeah that's that's amazing yeah
and um you know and speaking of Love let
youve you've been in situations you you
had mentioned earlier that where you
weren't in in a lovable relationships
and what did you mean by that you you
were with someone that you shouldn't
have been with what does that mean to
you
um are you talking about my my
ex-husband or just yeah the ex-husband
yeah um well that's kind of interesting
because we met and again it I was doing
really well I talk about this in the
book I was really you know in my walk
with God and um we started dating and
you know we we started having sex
outside of marriage and you know to he
was getting ready to deploy and mind you
I I had no idea what military life was
like I didn't know what I was getting
myself into I lived an hour away from
the military town but
um towards the end we started just
fighting a whole lot and um he went home
and he came back and he had his
engagement the engagement ring and for
me you know I love him for being my
daughter's dad but I wasn't in love with
him I was in love with the idea of being
married and I was 30 years old you know
so to me it was like my my clock was
ticking and I was rushing something that
didn't need to be but um so we um found
out I was pregnant on Saturday he
proposed Sunday and we were married
Monday and five days later he left and
um was deployed for a year so and and
that deployment wasn't wasn't really
that great they lost a soldier um during
that deployment and so he was coming
back to be a new father 21 21 new father
new stepfather to a 10-year-old um and
him and my daughter didn't get along you
know him and my my old older daughter
did not get along and so um and then the
deployment readjusting so I talk about
in the in in that in that chapter how um
it was just really all the cards were
just stacked up against us you know um
for it not to and I didn't help the
situation situation because I didn't
deal with the rejection in the marriage
very well I turned to that's that's
where I turned I was in church I was in
church I was going to groups in
church but I I still was not deal and
and I'm gonna I'm gonna say something
that's that that people if you're
watching whoever's watching this this is
what happens when people don't see
results in their walk with Christ and
they want to know why people backslide
and go back to their familiar
it's because they don't know how to deal
with it so whatever's comfortable to
them in their comfort zone in dealing
with it they'll go back to that and and
they see that as backsliding and they
not doing good but I think that's
progression when when people when we see
people going back to a comfort zone it's
never the same as when they did it when
they were not saved so but I um I would
go back to drinking and it just was a
mess it was terrible it it caused issues
with my daughter my my daughter went to
go live with her dad because I got a DUI
and um to this day I'm still dealing
with some of those issues with her I
still have to work some of those things
out and that's just part of the
consequence for me of making poor
choices and not dealing with stuff based
on I think if you just deal with things
head on instead of going back to the
Comfort Zone then then it would be
better but most times people go back to
what's Comfort to them now speaking of
comfort your path to entrepreneurialism
I mean that's not easy for people to
step in and you know and to carve a
career for yourself so tell me a little
bit about your path to
entrepreneurialism well you know it's
it's Little Steps at a time um Ryan uh
it's it's not an overnight thing like
um God told me two years ago before
Facebook live was even out he was like
step out and use what you got okay I had
my iPhone and I have my mouse and I'll
tell everybody so what I started doing
is just recording videos and it was just
amazing I did my first video um two
minutes long on romance 828 and in three
days there was a thousand views on that
video and I'm like oh my gosh this is
crazy so anytime there was something
that was put on my heart and people I
was just getting amazing feedback from
that you know um so I'm ENT preneurship
to me you know so many people have such
so many different ways of doing
entrepreneurship I think with with it
you have to find what works for you you
know what I mean um if getting up at 5
o'clock in the morning works for you
because sometimes what ends up happening
for me I get up at 7 and I'm up to 1 2 3
in the morning you know um doing stuff
so it's just not always a cookie cutter
way to get to where you got to go you
just got to find what works for you and
make sure your circle is small and you
have positive people in your circle that
will keep you right you know when you're
you're getting off track and focusing on
the negative things that's just one
thing I don't do I will not do you will
not catch me entertaining negative stuff
because it's just a waste of time and
energy I don't care you know what it is
if somebody isn't getting what I'm doing
that's fine you know I have too many
other things to focus on positive in my
life to you know focus on if somebody
likes me or if somebody's talking about
me or if somebody you know what I mean I
just don't have time for that um because
there's other stuff and new levels that
are coming and if I can't handle it on
this level I'm not going to be able to
handle it on the next level so
entrepreneurship like I said it's just
it it's what works and fits for you MH
what what would you say is your
definition of
entrepreneurialism like how would you
define
it being the best you at what your gift
and talent is is is what
entrepreneurship is to me if um you are
good at writing if you are good at
singing then then do those things
because we all have gifts and talents
and not step outside of that Arena too
many people want to step out of what's
not in their Arena and then they they
feel like they're failing at life well
because you're doing something you're
not supposed to you were given these
gifts you were given these talents for a
reason and do it in excellence you know
um I just wrote a book called
encouragement encouragement matters you
know entrepreneurship is being honest
with yourself you know um and so just
just doing what you are crafted to do
you know I'm not crafted to go sing I
would scare a whole audience away if I
did that you know what I mean but I'm
around singers all the time you know I
would I I would I I was around gospel
singers I'm always around them but I'm
not gonna get on a microphone and be
like yeah girl I got this no it's out of
my Arena you know but but other things
are in my Arena and I I just stay in my
Lane is what what I like to call it I
stay in my lane and do what God has
called me to do he's called me to
inspire people he's called me to love
people um I write books about it and
what he does with that and in and 2017
is just going to be an amazing year so I
I'm just encouraging y'all to sit back
and watch because Jamie Lynn has not
been doing this stuff just recently
because of Facebook live I've been doing
videos for two and a half years oh wow
so yeah amazing yeah so it's not just
jumping on Facebook live and doing it
it's it's I've seen it grow and I've
grown as a person with the things that
I've been through now your book you got
two books so I got two books you got two
books um but the recent book we're going
to talk about that in a second uh but
let's talk about diamond and the rough
so you know if people purchase it you
know what what can they expect um to
hear in that book what they're going to
hear is my Brokenness um the things that
Jamie Lynn experienced in life as my
like I was telling you earlier my walk
with Christ you know my mess ups you
know I I just I basically tell them
myself you know what I mean because if
somebody comes back and was like girl
you were promiscuous I know I was by the
book I told yall in the book um you were
drinking yes I was by the book I talk
about it you know so I don't leave any
room for the devil when I get onto a
platform to come at me because I've
already told it in the book and and in
this book I feel like there's something
for everybody to relate to and it it
makes it so raw and real and so
relatable you know that that you feel
like you're right there in the story
with me as I'm telling it so it's not
something you're GNA get and be like
I've had people I've had friends like
girl I'mma marinate on this I said
that's I said you're you're gonna read
it and let me tell you I promise you I
get a a an email this long talking about
Jamie I couldn't put the book down girl
that was so good and I'm like it's such
an honor to me like it's so humble
that I get to share my story with the
world and and and tell people you know
what it's okay you're going to get
through this because your journey is
your journey what you are experiencing
is not for you you know if people could
just grasp that losing that husband or
violent bankruptcy or anything negative
that we go through is never ever ever
ever for us it's always for somebody
else we may be in that because of a
choice we made but it's it's never for
us we're allowed to go through things
like I got in a car accident in the
beginning of December man I was thinking
Jesus thank you thank you Lord I don't
even know why you did this I don't know
why this was allowed but thank you and
I'm telling you four days five days
later I had $4,000 in my account to get
another car because I do videos somebody
amazing that that I connected with on
Facebook was like my wife and I want to
bless you and I'm just so thankful for
that person you know and and they they
they continue to bless my life you know
but that's a god connection you know and
you can't denounce that you know what I
mean so I just I'm so thankful for the
people that God places in my life that's
that's amazing so now let's talk a
little bit and then we have to cut for
commercial and then we have to uh then
we'll go through our second line of
questioning so uh second book tell us a
little bit it and what's the name of the
book again the book is called
encouragement matters and that book is
it's it's a very small book it's about
32 pages and actually it's going to be a
little bit longer than that because I I
just made the decision to put notes in
it like a page where people can write
notes but you know we live in a very
microwave Society you know people don't
want to always go through a book and get
some encouragement so I have like 31
topics and there's like three or four
sentences about this topic and a
scripture to go with it so it's just one
of those small quick devotional books
that God gave me um I had the titles for
that stuff about a month ago and then
last Tuesday it was just a week ago that
I sat down in my room and for like three
or four hours literally he finished
writing the
book so uh what's the where can people
find uh these books amazon.com um yes
you can look up diamond in the rough
Jamie Lynn and it's $12.99 on Amazon and
encouragement matters is still in the
final stages of being edited so that
should be up in the next couple of weeks
as well okay now uh we're going to cut
to Commercial and then we're going to
we're going to it looked like we had a
heavy heavy conversation in the uh the
comments there so some people were
arguing uh so we're going to bring up
some of those comments and uh we're also
going to um we're going to do our second
line of questioning where it's a little
bit more fun so we're not going to talk
about uh heavy situations so uh we'll
we'll be will be back in a few seconds
uh with the commercial and if you don't
mind to mute okay okay a web design
company in Calgary is taking the concept
of helping others to a whole new level
and as Robin Crawford reports it was an
Okanagan man who inspired them to use
their Tech skills to help people with
disabilities it gives me great pleasure
to introduce to you Michael D Hayes a
motivational speaker an entrepreneur and
a businessman Michael Haynes is doing it
all and I absolutely love it it's the
best job I've ever had in the beginning
Haynes admits that he didn't know how to
get his customer service Consulting
business off the ground and then he met
Ryan Perez with bowai creative for every
website that we sell we donate uh free
websites to entrepreneurs with
disabilities the Calgary based company
builds websites for businesses Haynes
knew he needed a website to promote
himself and Perez knew he had the tool
to help we were always talking about
working um um in the in doing something
for the disability for the for people
with disabilities um but we didn't know
what we were going to do and I thought
that this was a great time to um to do
something and and so we invented this
whole initiative like pretty much around
Michael bow tie creative built and
maintains an entire website for Hanes
free of charge he um
put my ideas into action yes I can hear
you and that made my my
job so much easier it's an initiative
that the four-person company is proud of
it's especially close to pre's heart
because he himself has dyslexia I paved
my own path and that's why this this
project means so much to me because I
want to help other people create their
paths B creative is now helping other
people with mental and physical
challenges build websites across North
America all because of Michael Haynes
he's a great guy and it's fantastic
working with him and I can't wait to see
what happens next for him if you know um
anyone that has a mental or physical
disability that wants to become an
entrepreneur or you know needs to needs
help to get started in the right
direction definitely check out our
website Haynes hopes with the kind of
support offered by Perez and his team
more people will find the confidence to
reach their goals I have a challenge you
have a challenge there is not a person
alive without a
challenge
I my challeng is more pronounced than
than yours Robin Crawford Global News
Colona
sorry
okay sound okay can you hear me now okay
we're here thanks karinda thanks for
letting me know okay sound okay let's uh
see here okay so I want to thank
everyone that had participated in the
broadcast so we had Horus we had Joshua
theen uh Susan uh and Richard
ranking and uh I think I said Patrick so
thank you guys all for participating in
the comment sections but there seems to
be people who put stuff on God or claim
something is God will um something is
God's Wills are
weak um what does that mean yeah I he'd
have to you'd have to you'd have to um
rephrase
horse because I guess he's saying that
people are weak because they you know
that they people are weak that they put
stuff on God's in God's hands and and
and I guess that's a lot you know like
there's a lot of criticisms you know cuz
not everyone um is going to believe in
your religion or whatever but what's
your response to that you know what
that's okay because um that that's their
choice I'm still going to love them I'm
not going to judge them for what they
don't believe but I can say this for
myself I can say I've personally
experienced this in my life
and and I can't say what other people's
encounters or what they believe or what
they don't believe but I can just and
and that's where it comes in where you
you really have to show love when when
you're you say to me when I say I'm a
Christian and if somebody doesn't agree
with what I agree with that doesn't make
it okay for me to be like okay well then
you know next no I want to love that
person even more so that doesn't
surprise me that somebody would say that
and that's okay that that's that's their
View and I respect that but at the same
time I I'm GNA stay my ground and not be
moved by what other people say or don't
say it doesn't make me a weak person
because I I have faith in Christ matter
of fact you know it makes me more
powerful not powerful but it you know I
just I am the woman that I am today and
I Inspire thousands of people you know
um if I can give life to somebody and
and if it's because I say Jesus or God
then then okay why does that matter but
at the end of the day Ryan I'm still
going to love anybody whether they
choose not to say God is the center of
their life or not that's their choice
that's the Free Will that we have in
America to make that choice and Joshua
theren says faith plus God or sorry
Faith plus family plus Health Plus money
equals wealth business baby uh so so I
mean and what is your relationship
before we go on to our second line of
questioning what what's your
relationship with
money my relationship with bunny I um I
believe if you it you have to handle it
well and that's an area of my life that
I am working on you have to be a good
Steward of it um and I believe you know
following the biblical principles you
know doing what you you have to do and
you will prosper but I don't believe in
chasing money I'm I'm going to be very
upfront with that I I I if I'm chasing
God in the the gifts and talents that he
has given me the money is going to come
because when and and this this is so
funny because in encouragement matters I
wrote this I said money is not the root
of all evil it's the way that we handle
money you know um people people will
always go back to that well money is the
root of all evil no money can't be evil
it's it's it's a piece of paper right
it's the person handling the money and
what you're doing with that money you
know um so I I believe you know you
definitely have to teach yourself how to
handle money um but I believe if you're
chasing your dreams and you're doing the
things that you're supposed to the money
will follow that's awesome that's
awesome and I mean like we don't always
have to have money right because if like
there's so many ways of of receiving
wealth there's so many ways that people
cuz you're in a bind you know even
someone giving you food maybe that's all
you need um so when you are Steward you
know to your principles and and and
you're you're doing something to benefit
the community because I I I I say every
time you know the whole process of
creation is an entrepreneurial process
it's like you're consciously bringing
something into the world that was never
there before so I think that it's
amazing that um you know that you have
done what you've done you've gone
through everything and you're still H
you're humble you know and you you're
not afraid to lay it all on the line and
say hey I'm not perfect right you're on
the path to perfect and that's why
people because people are not following
the hustle Zone because I'm 100% perfect
like I mean you see me doing these
push-ups and sometimes I can only do 15
and it's like people are following
because they like to see the progression
as opposed to not seeing anything at all
well and I truly believe this too Ryan
if you're loving people to the best of
your ability and you're giving
back you're to me that's a well-rounded
person you know because when you love
and give there is so much fulfillment in
that you know what I mean there's so
much fulfillment especially when you're
giving back and you're pouring into
people that are less fortunate than
yourself you that in itself is what
gives you Joy and and and the just an
inside fulfillment that you can't get
anywhere else MH okay uh so I'm just
going to see I think there was a comment
here disability Kenda said he has a
disability well Kender hit me up uh I'll
get you on the the um the M or the the
not the mailing list what am I saying
I'm I'm like flighty flighty today um
let's see here but I'll get you on the
on on the waiting list okay who else are
and then uh Susan says that you know
she's growing too you know she's you
know everyone is I think that you know
we're just moving to the next you know
we as long as we're
alive we still have a chance to do what
we want to do to be in the lives that we
because you mean you have your daughters
you have God has giving you that ability
and that chance to to to to be there and
that's that's amazing you know and a lot
of people get afraid of of those
challenges or they they're they get
depressed because they don't oh yeah oh
my gosh Ryan a year ago I was I wouldn't
leave my room for two months I was going
through something a year ago a year ago
I was laid up in the bed um and I just
want to say this especially to Susan
rejoice in your like I heard Pastor
Stephen verdict this morning say we have
to celebrate our successes we have
enough in our life to remind us of
things that we're not doing right and
and what I loved about what he said is
just celebrate the little successes and
and to me that is doing inch by inch you
know I didn't get where I am overnight
it was doing the little things that is
going to one day give me that platform
to be on a stage and encouraging
thousands if not millions of people one
day but you have to take the little
steps and and and rejoice in those
little steps that you're taking because
where you are today is not where you're
going to be next week because you're
going to grow in that week from where
you are but just little by little be you
have so many people on Facebook you know
you got to do this and you got to do
that and this is how you do it and and
nobody's saying slow down and and do the
Little Steps because it's the little
steps that matter that make the big
things even
better okay awesome and uh Horus had
said that he's like all right I'm out
take care of everyone remember you are
in control of your own stuff I mean yes
we are and I I have to agree you know we
are all in control you know whether
people choose to believe in God and
whether people choose to have a faith or
not have a faith we still you know we
still have the mechanisms to to change
our life you know right and and as long
as we're doing it it
wholeheartedly um with pure intentions
you know I can't see anything going
wrong with that right and I mean there's
going to be things that are outside of
our control but what Jamie is J like I'm
just paraphrasing here it's like what I
learned from this is that you know it
doesn't matter where you are as long as
you take that you know you take those
small steps and yes you you move forward
so so Jamie what's your what's your oh
what happened here no don't install uh
what sorry my computer's like linking um
what is your favorite
food Mexican food I love Mexican food
yes Mexican food Pico Deo you can just
give me buckets of that stuff and I'll
just have a field day and it's healthy
and calorie
free so what's your favorite
dessert um I don't have a favorite
dessert I'm not a big I don't like
sweets that much you give me chips and
sauce and I'm good to go really true
story like I chocolate cake don't give
me chocolates I'm not a big chocolate
girl I'm not a mushy you know I'm not I
can be that kind of it but I just I'm
not a sweet person I mean like candy
wise yeah H in terms of um music what's
the the what's the best music to dance
to oh hip-hop for sure and not this
newer stuff like you know back in the
day how old are you Ryan 3 or 33 see so
you'll remember like jod doy all them
back in the day you were like in grade
school you know back then when the music
was real good yeah you know I still have
fun to that but some of the stuff the
kids have now is kind of fun but for me
you know um yeah that's fun I love to
dance dancing is my favorite thing to do
like when I was a teenager like that was
my drug I used to go to the club and
like there there was this teenage Club
back home and so I would go every
[Music]
weekend you well JY man that's classic
like you just you hit the spot cuz I me
like the like that was real R&B music
and
Al wow wow w
s nice sure you sure don't know nothing
about
that so uh what Michael Jack I asked
this question yesterday and I'm gonna
ask it again so Michael Jackson or
Prince which one Michael Jackson yeah I
had his
jacket I like Made Up dances to all his
songs when I was like oh yes Michael all
the way Michael all the way okay all the
way now um if you had a magic Wan where
would you go in the world and
why that's interesting you know what I
would go to Paris because my daughter
wants to go to Paris and I would take
her to Paris with me so I would go to
Paris um can I pick another place I
would go to Africa I would go to Africa
because I've I love the African culture
I always have I don't know what it is
about the culture I just love the
culture um and would just love to take
my 20-year-old and want we wanted to go
to Africa we still do like it's not
something you have a specific place that
you would go would you go to South
Africa would you go to uh Nigeria would
you go
to um you know what I don't I don't have
a specific place you know what I mean I
would just probably hit different places
because it's just like they probably
they're so different in different areas
it would be just nice to see how they
live in their culture actually there's a
place called the Frist here in um
Nashville and my daughter and I went to
that and they were just showing like the
oh my gosh it was so amazing it was the
African culture and even how they do
funerals there are so different than us
like they carve out like a mermaid and
they Carri the people around the town
for like a week and I'm like oh that's
so interesting like you know and and and
so it just it's it's very intriguing um
I just love culture in I just love
culture yeah same same here and my my
ex- fiance she's from Ghana and um you
know she's saying that you know people
don't cry at the funerals like they
party they have a lot of fun I mean like
do you know that that's what we're
supposed to do like it it's supposed to
be opposite like when when babies are
born we celebrate in America when people
die we mourn but we're we're supposed to
like not MN a baby being born but like
celebrate their life when a person dies
for to celebrate I tell I tell my
daughters and see it's going on record
and it'll be in my will no we ain't
crying at my funeral I'm playing don't
worry be happy and we all gonna get
up you know we're don't worry be happy
that's when we played at my funeral
because we ain't doing no Amazing Grace
How Sweet the Sound I'll come I'll come
back and Haun you
no no I'm going to seriously have a
slide and they're gonna be dancing and
they're just gonna be shaking their head
like this is Jamie Lynn Jamie Lynn well
thank you so much uh Jamie for um you're
welcome for hopping in so if you don't
mind to put yourself on mute there and
um I'll I'll talk to you after the show
is um off air uh so folks
people's paths are people's paths um you
know when I bring people onto the hustle
zone I'm not here to judge I'm not here
to condemn you know when you come on the
show though it's a raw show so you know
I I'm just trying to I I'm assuming
everything is perfect and I'm going to
check your story out um and but in no
way uh do I you know put my guest on
here to to to judge their path because
you know like I said in earlier hustle
zones uh that
inaction is or is worse than action you
know you can have an imperfect action
but an action is an action and a lot of
people don't have the courage to take
actions and here we have a woman that
you know her purpose her why is Jesus
Christ you know do I have to subscribe
to her religion no and I'm not I'm not
religious in any sense of the way but I
do understand what is pushing her
forward and I do understand what her
Inspirations are and the fact that you
know Jamie came in and she was raw
um uh with with her story and and you
know and she was just humble about where
she was at I think it's amazing and I
think she's going to be really
successful and and I do encourage her um
you know to come back and we could talk
on some more subjects but before we go
Jamie I totally forgot
this wouldn't be the hustle Zone if uh
before you leave but uh I'm going to
need you to do I I'm going to do a call
and response so I'm going to say welcome
to the and then you're GNA scream hustle
Zone as loud as you can oh okay all
right so there's gonna be
an it's all good
okay welcome to the hust
Z I love it I love it so some people are
like to the house I'm like no do it
again my cheerleader came out that was
my cheerleader Amy that's awesome I
enjoyed this conversation and you know
it just was raw it was um you know you
you didn't leave anything out and I
thank you for sharing your story you
know um thank you and I wish you luck
with your books and please come into the
comments and post share you know share
this video too as as much as you can and
uh you know post your links because I'm
sure that there's a few people here that
that will buy the book and um please
support us please support all of us all
of us entrepreneurs out here trying to
do something good for everyone and uh
and I hope you had fun so thank you guys
for showing up we're going to play one
more clip and then we're out